<NIKITA AVEROCHKIN>

</FRONTEND DEVELOPER>

+7 915 543 85 25

aser-14@bk.ru

Voronezh, Russia

Portfolio website

Hey! I'm creative and constantly growing developer with more than three years of experience who loves crafting products that people love. I'm eager to apply my expertise, solving extraordinary problems and bringing profit to customers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

IT_ONE | Moscow, Russia (Remote)
May 2023 — Current

I was developing corporate application portals:

- Worked with several code bases: on React.js and on HPSM using pure ES5 JavaScript.
- Carried out organizational tasks of the team.

I improved UI/UX user satisfaction metrics by ~40% through optimizing performance, refactoring layout of core components in the process of migration from pure CSS and also creating UI Kit from scratch for an app which is used by 25.000 bank employees. I reduced the build time of a React.js project by 1.5 times and created detailed project documentation which sped up the onboadring process.

Stack: React.js, JavaScript, CSS, Styled Components, Webpack, HP Service Manager, RAD

Frontend Developer

Calendaria | Almaty, Kazakhstan (Remote) November 2022 — May 2023

I was a frontend lead of an enterprise IAM portal:

- Designed frontend architecture on React.js and application layout from scratch.
- Analysed technical assignment and project needs.
- Mentored two junior developers, conducted interviews.

I successfully accomplished the full development process within contract period, achieving the main goal of digitizing up to 80% of the company's document flow. My efforts have resulted in an application that is actively used by 4.500 employees.

Stack: React.js, TypeScript Redux-toolkit, React-JSS, Ant Design, Webpack, Keycloak

Frontend Developer

Tecom | Nizhny Novgorod, Russia (Remote) November 2021 — November 2022

I was developing a remote device tracking system:

• Fixed, refactored, wrote new logic on React.js and achieved 80% test coverage by unit and e2e tests.

 Developed core libraries, including a corporate Ulkit with storybook, as well as a library of readymade utilities.

I released MVP versions of 3 editor-like interfaces libraries (pdf, diagrams, charts) and received positive feedback from customers. My contribution in migration to newer React.js version without class components made development process more efficient.

Stack: React.js, React-JSS, Material UI, Intl, Redux, Reselect, Jest, Playwright, Ierna

Frontend Developer

Julius | London, United Kingdom (Remote)
December 2020 - November 2021

I developed UI of ML platform for managing backend services:

- Implemented many features, such as theming and internalization.
- Worked on accessible responsive design and refactored styles by utilizing modern SCSS features.
- Developed complex components: large tables, scatter charts, trees.

I reduced page loading times by implementing Relay data-fetching mechanisms. I enhanced application accessibility up to 90% in Lighthouse and made it pixel-perfect identical to Figma.

Stack: React.js, TypeScript, SCSS, Ant Design, GraphQL, React Relay

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Voronezh State University

2019-2023 | Voronezh, Russia

Faculty: Applied math, informatics and mechanics. Direction: Fundamental informatics and information technologies

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (FLUENT), RUSSIAN (NATIVE)